你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第六集
5月8日
奥莉薇亚想把分居期
Olivia wants to extend the trial separation
再延长半年
another six months.
谁都不想先提那个"离"字
Neither one of us is willing to bring up the "D" word.
结婚时  还自以为选对了
When you get married, you think you found the one.
你怎么会知道呢
I mean, how do you know?
谁又会知道呢
I mean, how does anyone know?
这种事情上我可不是权威
Well, I'm no authority on these matters.
但如果你想休息一段时间
But if you want to take some time off,
处理这些事情
work things out--
工作是唯一
Work's the one thing
能让我不去想这些烂事的
that keeps my mind off the situation.
说说  咱们的小实验怎么样了
So tell me, how goes our little experiment?
真高兴你问这个
I'm glad you asked.
你觉得凳子上那位男士如何
What do you make of that man on the bench?
似乎是喝多了撑的
Looks like he tied one on a little too tight.
我猜你肯定不会相信
Bet you'd never believe me if I told you
他是个小提琴奇才
he was a violin prodigy
在交响乐团演奏过两年
who played two years with the philharmonic.
嗜酒毁了他的事业
His penchant for the bottle cut his career short.
凭这个怎么阻止恐怖袭击呢
How exactly does this help stop terrorism?
要教机器识别出坏人
Before I could teach the machine to find bad people,
得先教它了解普通人
I had to teach it people in general.
我给它编程以识别异常因素
I programmed it to identify outliers:
在某些方面  比较有意思的个体
individuals who are... interesting in some way.
要教一台机器了解人性的复杂之处
To teach a machine the complexities of human nature--
我无意冒犯  哈罗德  但是
I mean, no offense, Harold, but...
像你这么内向的人做这个合适吗
is someone as introverted as you the best person for the job?
莫莉・科尔是谁呢
Who's Molly Cole?
我不知道
I have no idea.
24岁的纽约大学研究生
24-year-old graduate student at NYU.
主修天体物理
Major in Astrophysics.
这里显示昨晚你跟她在一起
Says you were with her last night.
看来工作根本不是唯一
So work must not be the only thing
莫莉・科尔
能让你不去想分居那些事的
that's kept your mind off the separation.
你想说什么吧
So what's your point?
你问我机器是否有能力
You asked me if the machine was capable
学会理解人性
of learning human nature.
我说  它有
I'm saying it already is.
它通过监控所有人来学习
It's learning by watching everyone.
包括你
Even you.
奇怪
That's odd.
怎么了
What?
在栏杆边画画的女人
That woman painting at the railing.
格蕾斯・亨德里克斯
Grace Hendricks.
自由艺术家
Freelance artist.
在一家儿童收容所做志愿者
Volunteers at a children's shelter.
除了这些  我没看出什么异常
But beyond that, no anomalies that I can see.
为何把她选出来呢
Why did it show her to us?
肯定是故障
Must be a bug.
我要再检查一遍代码
I'll go over the code again,
看看是否有遗漏
see if I missed something.
至少机器向我们展示了它品位不俗啊
At least the machine is showing us it has good taste.
小熊
Bear!
我们讨论界限问题时怎么说来着
What did we discuss about boundaries?
早  芬奇
Morning, Finch.
来得正好  里瑟先生
Impeccable timing, Mr. Reese.
我刚开始研究新号码
I've just begun digging into our latest number.
糖屑给得有点少了
A little stingy on the sprinkles.
格雷汉姆・惠勒
Graham Wyler.
42岁的已婚男
A 42-year-old family man.
跟妻子一起经营远洛克威的一家小五金商店
Owns a small hardware store with his wife in Far Rockaway.
郊区啊
The suburbs?
以前没出现过那边的号码
Never had a number out there before.
很遗憾  谋杀并不受区域限制
Unfortunately, murder isn't confined to a zip code.
我去盯这家人
I'll get eyes on the family.
以后别去这家买了
I wouldn't go back to this place.
威胁评估活动
不同选区犯罪率
远洛克威
惠勒1997年从印第安纳的韦恩堡搬到这里
Wyler moved to the city from Fort Wayne, Indiana, in 1997.
他跟妻子康妮结婚14年了
He's been married to his wife Connie for 14 years.
-女儿呢  -伊西
- And the daughter? - Izzy.
沙堡初中的优秀学生
Honor student at Sandburg Junior High
足球明星
and soccer star.
威勒的房贷还款没问题
Wyler's mortgage is affordable.
信用良好
His credit is good.
家里只有一辆车  没有贷款
Family only owns one car, free and clear.
所以这位是全纽约最无趣的男人
So we found the most boring man in New York.
看到通气孔上的黑色污渍了没
See the black smudges in the air vent?
是马达故障造成的
'cause your motor's fried.
一小时后再来  我帮你修好
Come back in an hour, and I'll have it fixed for you.
太好了  我该给你多少钱
Great. How much do I owe you?
下次买钻头来找我
Just buy your next drill with me,
就算扯平了
we'll call it even.
好的  星期六没问题
All right, Saturday's fine.
好的  再见
Okay, bye-bye.
贝克特太太的电话
That was Mrs. Beckett.
她扮可怜求我帮家长教师联谊会募捐
She just guilted me into helping with the PTA fundraiser.
格雷汉姆・惠勒
复制手机
已连接
离开你她是寸步难行
She wouldn't know what to do without you.
其实我也一样
Neither would I, for that matter.
可能是在帮他的大砍刀找磨刀石呢
Probably looking for the sharpening kit for his machete.
有什么可以帮你的  先生
Can I help you, sir?
我说了  来前先给电话
I told you to call before you showed up.
你想让我妻子发现吗
You trying to get me busted with my wife?
随便吧
Whatever, man.
你到底要不要
You want these or not?
要  赶紧的好吧
Yeah, just make it fast, all right?
看来威勒经营的
Looks like Wyler might be dealing
不只是电动工具啊  芬奇
more than power tools, Finch.
训练怎么样
How's practice?
我们练了一整天往返跑
We did shuttle runs all day.
-是吗  似乎很有趣  -是啊
- Yeah? Sounds like fun. - Yeah.
想看看吗
Want to see something?
布鲁斯・斯普林斯汀的演唱会门票
Tickets to Bruce Springsteen?
前排座位  为你妈妈生日准备的
Front row seats, for mom's birthday.
很酷是吧
Pretty awesome, right?
其实有点逊  爸爸
It's kinda lame, dad.
那这个呢
Well, how about this, then?
不是吧  你修好了
No way! You fixed it!
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧芬奇  这家伙是圣人
All right, Finch, this guy's a saint.
我可不敢确定
I'm not so sure.
我仔细查看了他的工作经历
I took a closer look at his employment history.
看不出他怎么会有钱搬到东部
Hard to see how he had the money to move east,
何况还要支撑城市生活的费用
much less, support a city lifestyle.
也许他遇到了一位隐型富豪
Maybe he met a reclusive billionaire?
其实他没遇到
In the event that he didn't,
我给韦恩堡那边打了几个电话
I made a few phone calls around Fort Wayne,
自称是系谱学家调查家谱图
claiming to be a genealogist working on a family tree.
然后查到了一条有趣的记录
And I did uncover one record of interest.
什么记录
And what's that?
他的死亡证明
His death certificate.
真正的格雷汉姆・惠勒死于1997年
The real Graham Wyler died in 1997.
讣告
格雷汉姆・惠勒
你跟踪的这人偷了他的身份
Whoever you've been following stole his identity
并一直盗用了15年
and has been using it for the past 15 years.
借尸还魂
He's ghosting.
以死人的名义活着
Built a life on a dead man's name.
不如先别管这个人
Might be better if we were less concerned
现在的身份
with who this man is,
重点查清他过去的身份
and more concerned with who he was.
下午好
Afternoon.
以前没见过你
I haven't seen you around here before.
刚来的吗
You new in town?
只是路过
Passing through, actually.
很遗憾  路过不够快
Unfortunately, not fast enough.
这里禁止停车
You're in a no parking zone.
就警告一下行吗
Any way you could let me off with a warning?
要我动用小额备用金支付吗
So shall I pay this out of petty cash?
在郊区跟踪比在城市里难多了
Harder to tail someone in the suburbs than in the city.
听说了
I heard.
你"西装男"那套玩不转了
Your man-in-the-suit routine doesn't exactly play.
正巧
As it happens,
有幢精致的三居室别墅
there's a quaint three-bedroom
刚刚开始出售
that's just gone on the market
正好位于惠勒家对面
across from the Wyler's home.
你可以明天搬进去
You can move in tomorrow.
搬进去
Move in?
你们会成为邻居
You're gonna be neighbors.
我还买了一辆新车
I also procured a new vehicle,
一套合适的行头
an appropriate wardrobe,
一套高尔夫球具
and a set of golf clubs.
伪装身份还有个关键元素
There is one element of your cover
你得自己搞定
that you'll have to acquire on your own.
约翰
John.
真遗憾  听说你跟那位记者
I'm sorry to hear that it didn't work out
玛克辛没成
with that reporter Maxine.
我会没事的
I'll get over it.
其实我在想
I was actually thinking...
我们应该多聚聚
we should spend a little more time together.
是吗
Is that so?
这次是怎么回事
What is it this time?
更强大的玩家  更复杂的伪装
More power players or cover-ups?
也不算
Not exactly.
佐伊・摩根
Zoe Morgan...
做我的妻子好吗
will you be my wife?
搬家公司
记得那次你曾救我
Remember when you saved me
免遭雇佣杀手的折磨和杀害吗
from being tortured and killed by corporate hit men?
这下我们扯平了
Consider us even.
这么说你不想我
That mean you don't want me
抱你进门了吗
to carry you across the threshold?
等这一切结束
When this is over,
我没准儿会和你争夺狗狗的抚养权
I might have to fight you for custody of the dog.
已经开始想我了吗  哈罗德
Miss me already, Harold?
其实  我是想感谢摩根女士
Actually, I wanted to thank Ms. Morgan
提供专业帮助
for offering her services.
神秘的郊区老爸
Suburban dad with a mysterious secret?
怎么抗拒得了
How could I resist?
再说  得有人看着约翰
Plus, somebody had to see to it
免得他炸掉整条街
that John didn't burn down the block.
我们等着瞧吧
We'll see what happens.
现在  重点是确定惠勒的身份
Right now, our main concern is to ID Wyler,
查出他到底是谁
figure out who he really is.
想到变成惠勒好友的办法了吗
Any ideas on how to become the Wyler's new best friends?
想到几个
A few.
我会去拜访惠勒的店
I'll visit Wyler at his store,
告诉他我们刚刚搬到对门
tell him we just moved across the street.
一旦有了交集
Once we've established contact,
我们就能引导他们家来
we'll be able to manipulate the family into--
约翰  只是门铃
John, it's a doorbell.
不要第一天就来个枪杀女童军  可以吗
Let's try not to shoot any girl scouts on our first day, okay?
很抱歉打扰你们
Sorry to bother you.
只是想过来
Just wanted to stop by
欢迎一下新邻居
and welcome you to the neighborhood.
-我是康妮・惠勒  -格雷汉姆
- I'm Connie Wyler. - Graham.
约翰・坎贝尔
John Campbell.
美国科幻小说黄金时代的开山鼻祖
这是我妻子佐伊
This is my wife Zoe.
很高兴见到你们
It's nice to meet you both.
给你们做了点吃的
I made you guys some ambrosia.
盘子可以有空再还
Just bring the dish back anytime.
我们就住对门
We're right across the street.
看起来真美味
This looks delicious.
下午大家都过来一起烧烤
We're having some people over this afternoon for a barbecue.
有空的话你们也过来吧
You should stop by if you're not busy.
我们会去的
Well, we'll be there.
太好了  下午见
Great. See you then.
挺容易嘛
That was easy.
谢谢
Thanks.
我早就注意到你的车了
Couldn't help but notice your car earlier.
太漂亮了
Thing of beauty.
花了你多少钱
How much she set you back?
其实是公司的车
Actually, it's a company car.
天  我肯定是入错行了
Man, I must have picked the wrong business.
你做什么工作
What do you do?
销售私人安防系统
I sell private security systems.
家用的  公司用的
Homes, offices.
如果你感兴趣的话
You know, if you're interested,
有些设备我可以给你不错的折扣
I could get you a great deal on some equipment.
不用了谢谢
No thanks.
我属于守旧派  玩不转高科技
Kind of old-school, low-tech.
我刚加固了家里门和窗户上的锁
I reinforced the locks on my doors and windows.
住在这里  有这些就足够安防了
That's pretty much all the security you need around here.
看来你心里很有数
Sounds like you've got it all figured out.
就是不知道怎么增加店内客流
Except how to get people into my store.
真是越来越难
It's getting harder and harder
跟大型连锁店竞争了
to keep up with the big box chains.
老实人辛苦谋生却无人欣赏
No one appreciates an honest man trying to make a living.
敬这句话
I'll drink to that.
你俩住在洛克威多久了
How long have the two of you been living in Rockaway?
差不多十年了
Oh, about ten years.
我母亲生病后我和格雷汉姆就搬过来了
Graham and I moved here after my mother got sick,
想帮上点忙
so we came out to help.
你们呢
What about you guys?
你怎么认识约翰的
How did you meet John?
我被困在了...
I was, um, stranded...
城里的危险地区
in a bad part of town.
他带了我一程
And he gave me a ride.
然后我们整晚都在城里
And we actually spent the rest of the evening
游车河
running around the city.
约翰让我想起了当年的格雷汉姆
Oh, you know, John kind of reminds me of Graham,
我们刚到这的时候  有点安定不下来
when we first moved out here, kind of restless.
别担心  他会静下来的
Don't worry, he'll calm down.
再来瓶酷乐酒吗
Another Wine Cooler?
来杯曼哈顿怎么样
What about a Manhattan, up?
怎么调
How do you make that?
-来  我做给你看  -好的
- Come on, I'll show you. - Okay.
爸  你看到我的项链了吗
Dad, have you seen my necklace?
修好后就没见过
No, not since I fixed it.
如果你破天荒地整理下房间
If you cleaned your room once in a millennium--
我继续去找
I'll keep looking for it.
我们在费城有什么熟人吗
Who do we know in Philadelphia?
没  从没去过  怎么了
No one, never been there. Why?
有张明信片
This postcard came.
天啊  好可爱
Oh, my Gosh! He's adorable.
真招人喜欢
Oh, you're so cute!
惠勒家收
洛克威市桃花街2828号
乖宝贝噢
Who's a good boy?
你能替我烤会儿吗
Would you mind manning the grill for a moment?
当然
Sure.
惠勒被什么东西吓到了
Wyler's spooked about something.
他隐藏的事  没告诉任何人
Whatever he's hiding, he kept it from everyone.
康妮一无所知
Connie's in the dark.
看看我们能不能查清点什么
Let's see if we can shed some light, then.
你有化妆刷吗
You got a makeup brush?
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Nonopig  芒果妖怪  沙沙A  紫玉  大黑  板栗桑
翻译：阿好  天朝直属   时间轴：GGwhywhy   JimmyBeck
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监：阿好
卡特
Carter.
能帮我查个指纹吗
You think you can run a print for me?
又发现坏人了
You find another bad guy?
正在努力发现中
That's what I'm trying to find out.
这人看上去不像坏人啊
That guy doesn't look so bad.
至于指纹  期望值别太高
As for the print, I wouldn't hold your breath.
只是部分指纹
It's a partial.
从费城查起吧
Start with a search in Philadelphia.
我们不会要飞去费城  是吧
We're not getting on a plane to Philly, are we?
目前不用
Not at the moment.
现在干嘛
What now?
等着
We wait.
你都来了  热闹还会远吗
The party never stops when you're around.
这里的人都找什么乐子呢
What do these people do for fun?
问倒我了
Beats me.
有什么主意吗
Got any ideas?
? Boom boom boom boom ?
? I'm gonna shoot you right down ?
郊区生活也没那么糟嘛
Suburbs might not be so bad after all.
跟不跟呢  亲爱的
In or out...dear?
我几时临阵脱逃过
Ever known me to run from a fight?
一对A
Pair of aces.
两对
Two pair.
? And walk that walk ?
来杯柠檬水吗  先生  50美分
Lemonade, sir? 50.
给您
Here you go.
昨晚休息得好吗  里瑟先生
Have a good night's rest, Mr. Reese?
估计比惠勒好点
Think I fared better than Wyler.
他看上去疲惫不堪
He looks exhausted.
你今早给车换机油了吗
Did you change the oil in the car this morning?
没  我忘了  抱歉
No, I forgot. Sorry.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
抱歉了  劳埃德
Sorry about that, Lloyd.
你认识那人吗
You know that guy?
不  他肯定是把我错认成别人了
No, he must have confused me with someone else.
你听到了吗  芬奇
You hear that, Finch?
似乎不只是认错人
Sounds like more than a case of mistaken identity.
神秘男跟个朋友一起走了
Mystery man just took off with a friend.
可能就是寄明信片给惠勒的人
Could be the same men that sent Wyler the postcard.
我想他们可不是来城里叙旧的
Something tells me they're not in town for a reunion.
警探
Detective.
找到那家伙了
I found your guy.
他被捕过一次
He was only arrested once,
罪名是91年的一次非法入侵
for a misdemeanor B&E, back in '91,
不过他因以一系列抢劫案和非法入室被通缉
but was wanted for a string of robberies and home invasions.
他是职业大盗
He was a career thief.
我觉得费城警察肯定
I'm sure Philly PD would love
想找他谈谈
to have a talk with him.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
他叫劳埃德
First name's Lloyd.
劳埃德・普鲁特
Lloyd Pruitt.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
蒙的
Wild guess.
他有同伙吗
Did he work with a crew?
对  有两个
Yeah, a couple other guys.
克里斯・沃恩和丹尼尔・伯恩赛德
Chris Vaughn and Daniel Burnside.
他们干得相当顺手
They had a good run
直到97年抢劫珠宝店被捕
until they got caught taking a jewelry store in '97.
入狱12年
Did 12 years.
我猜那位劳埃德没干那一票
I guess your guy Lloyd missed that job
或者在被捕之前逃跑了
or disappeared before they got picked up.
他忙着化身格雷汉姆・惠勒
He was busy becoming Graham Wyler,
洗白背景
giving himself a clean slate.
他离开得正是时候
He picked a good time to run.
他们被捕的那票抢劫案中
That job they got busted on,
沃恩对一名手无寸铁的保安开枪
Vaughn shot an unarmed guard.
他是危险分子
He's dangerous.
感谢帮忙  卡特
Thanks for your help, Carter.
干得漂亮
Good job!
-你踢得真好  -谢谢妈
- Good play out there. - Thanks, mom.
芬奇  沃恩在这里
Finch, Vaughn's here.
我去找他聊聊
I'm gonna have a few words with him.
不是吧
No way!
那是谁的车
Whose car is that?
等等  站远点
Wait. Stay back.
来电显示被屏蔽
车真不幸啊  劳埃德
Sucks about the car, Lloyd.
不过很高兴今天能撞见你
Nice running into you today, though.
我们出来喝一杯如何
Why don't we grab a drink?
城里那家撞墙酒吧
The Wallbanger, in the city.
明天下午
Noon tomorrow.
我们有些事儿要办
We've got some catching up to do.
芬奇  看来惠勒的过去阴魂不散啊
Finch, looks like Wyler's past has come back to haunt him.
你可以通过手机来访问
You'll have access to all the camera feeds
所有的摄像头
through your cell phone.
那这个警报器
And this alarm system,
它会向警局报案吗
does it call the local police?
不不不
No-no, no.
信号会发送给一个私人行动队
It sends a signal to a private response team.
你做得对
You're doing the right thing.
康妮还没从车着火的事里缓过来
Yeah, Connie's still shaken up about the car fire.
依我们看  可能是些孩子干的
And for all we know, it could be a couple of teenagers.
怎么样了  哈罗德
How are we doing, Harold?
马上就好  老板
Almost finished, boss.
好了  如果惠勒的老伙计试图闯入
Okay, if Wyler's old crew attempt to gain access to the house,
我们会看见
we'll see them coming.
沃恩很聪明
Vaughn's been smart so far.
警察在车上找不到证据
Cops couldn't find the evidence on the SUV
证明是犯罪行为
to point to a culprit.
说到沃恩  我梳理了他的档案
Speaking of Vaughn, I combed through his files.
他们那伙人做的每票案子里
In each of the jobs that he and his crew have pulled,
保险箱都是用一种
a safe was cracked
叫做"锁操纵"的技术打开的
using a technique called "lock manipulation."
不用钻孔  不用工具
No drilling, no tools.
只用耳朵听
All of it done by ear.
这是种失传的绝技
This is a lost art.
但是在最后一票抢劫时
But in the last heist,
情况有所不同
there was a difference.
沃恩开枪打了保安
Vaughn shot the guard
逼着珠宝店的经理打开保险箱
to motivate the jewelry store manager to open the safe.
就是惠勒缺席的那次
The one job Wyler didn't show up for.
他是开锁人
He was the safecracker.
最后那票没参加
Bailed on the last job.
他们把失手被捕归罪于他
They blame him for getting locked up.
这点他们今天下午会面时
A detail they'll, no doubt, remind him of
绝对会提醒他的
when they meet this afternoon.
宝贝  你在吗
Honey, you in here?
我刚挂了保险公司打来的电话
So I just got off the phone with the insurance company.
他们说调查员最早也要
They say they can't send an investigator out
下周才能过来
till next week.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
我要去店里取点东西
I need to go get something for the store.
好的  稍等一下好吗
Okay, well, hang out for a second, okay?
他们说要想拿到赔偿金就
They say they can't cover the cost of a rental...
先别管了
It can wait!
好吗
All right?
听着
Look...
我必须走了  好吗
I need to go, okay?
我们以后再解决行吗
Can we handle this later?
我自己能解决
I can handle it myself.
不过打几个电话罢了
It's a couple of stupid phone calls.
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
没什么需要操心的
Nothing you need to worry about.
格雷汉姆  你要是认为
Graham, if there's something going on
有什么事不能告诉我
you think you can't tell me,
别那么想
get over it.
不管发生什么  我们都一起承担
Whatever it is, we'll figure it out together.
我几个钟头就回来
I'll be back in a few hours.
格雷汉姆  你要去哪
Graham, where are you headed?
赶去城里的火车
Catching a train into the city.
我正好要去见个客户
I'm meeting a client there.
带你一程吧
Let me give you a lift.
节约点时间
Save you some time.
谢了
Thanks.
适应平静的生活需要点过程
Quiet life takes some getting used to.
不合你的节奏吧
Not your speed, huh?
好多做私人安防的
You know, a lot of guys in home security
以前都在执法部门工作
used to be in law enforcement.
你以前是警察之类的吗
Were you a cop or something?
我不是
Not me.
规则太多
Too many rules.
打破规则的感觉更好
Always had more fun breaking them.
我们早晚要长大的  是吧
Guess we all got to grow up sometime, right?
那时真没想到我也会
Certainly never thought I would.
怎么变了
What changed?
自己
Me.
以前只需照顾自己
Used to just look out for myself.
现在要照顾康妮和伊西
Now I look out for Connie and Izzy.
为了她们我不惜一切
Nothing I wouldn't do for them.
看来惠勒的过去
Seems that Wyler's past
威胁到的不仅是他的生命  还有他的婚姻
threatens not only his life but his marriage as well.
我去去就回
I'll be back.
我从没见过他如此生气
I've never seen him angry like that.
可能他只是事情太多了
He's probably just got a lot on his mind.
你知道的  车子还有
You know, with the car and the--
不是这样的
It's not that.
自我认识他以来
The whole time I've known him,
格雷汉姆向来遇事不慌  胸有成竹
Graham has always been the one with the solution.
但今天  我简直都不认识他了
But today, I didn't even know who that was.
我还没问过你们是怎么认识的
You know, I never asked you how you two met.
我们在新泽西的斯普林斯汀演唱会上相遇
We met at a Springsteen concert in Jersey.
有个变态不停调戏我
This creep wouldn't stop hitting on me.
格雷汉姆就突然出现了
And suddenly Graham appeared.
我以前从没见过他
I'd never seen him before,
不过他假装是我的男友
but he pretended to be my boyfriend
好赶走那个变态
so the other guy would go away.
我只能说
And I could just tell
他身上有些与众不同的地方
there was something different about him.
那一瞬间足以改变一生
That one moment changed your whole life.
是啊
Yeah.
你和约翰相遇时也是这种感觉吗
Is that what it was like when you first met John?
老实说
I can honestly say
没有他我今天不会在这里
that I wouldn't be here without him.
很难找到可以依靠的人
It's rare to find someone you can depend on.
准备好开玩了吗
Ready to have some fun?
你很擅长将人们
You're good at connecting people
和他们不想揭露的事情联系起来
to the things they don't want the world to know.
你又有多擅长
How good are you at finding connections
发现无人所知的联系呢
that no one knows exists?
告诉我那两个人的关系
Try to tell me if there's a correlation
那个牛仔和的士司机
between the cowboy and the taxi driver.
五代表亲
Fifth cousins?
真的吗
Really?
我们还真是身处大熔炉啊
We do live in the great melting pot.
好吧
Okay.
另外两个人的关系
What's the association
这名跑步者和
between this jogger and--
又是她
It's her again.
你在格蕾丝・亨德克斯身上发现什么有意思的吗
So you've found something interesting on Grace Hendricks?
没有
No?
那她和公园里其他人有没有关系
Then is she connected to anyone else in the park?
我还以为修复成功了
I thought I fixed this.
这女人的生活中你没发现任何异常
You haven't found a single anomaly in this woman's life.
她诚实  正直
She's honest, decent,
似乎没有任何不可告人的秘密
doesn't seem to have any dark secrets.
对任何人都没有恶意
Doesn't harbor ill will toward anyone.
这正是她与众不同的地方
Which is what sets her apart from everyone else here.
还有对查尔斯・狄更斯的热爱
That and a passionate love for Charles Dickens.
我在这里打车就好
I can take a cab back from here.
谢谢你载我来
Thanks for the ride.
不用谢
You're welcome.
换新形象了
Trying a new look?
怀念以前的样子
More like missing my old one.
那些人在里面待了半小时了
Your boys have been in there for half an hour.
他来了  你欠我二十刀
He showed. You owe me 20 bucks.
你们怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
这个说来就有趣了
That is a real fun story.
当时我在工作
I was at work.
刷碗工
Dishwasher.
我这种前科犯只能找到那种工作
Only kind of job a con like me could get.
老板给我看了一张脸书上的照片
My boss shows me this Facebook photo.
他在纽约的崽子
Some babe he's plowing in New York.
我看了
I look.
简直不敢相信我的眼睛
I can't believe my eyes.
劳埃德・普鲁特
There's Lloyd Pruitt...
就站在照片的背景里
standing in the background of this photo.
我久违的朋友
My long lost friend.
神采飞扬
Smiling, laughing,
他漂亮的女儿穿着名牌校服站在他身边
beautiful daughter next to him in her nice school sweater.
你混得真是不错啊  劳埃德
It's a hell of a life you've made for yourself, Lloyd.
希望我也能成天卖锤子
Wish I was spending my days selling hammers.
比在州监狱里蹲12年强多了
Beats 12 years in the Fromhold State Penitentiary.
只有12年吗  感觉好像更久
Was it 12? It felt longer.
是啊  感觉好像50年
Yeah, felt like 50.
这能怪我
That's my fault?
我告诉过你那活儿很危险
I told you the job was dangerous.
但你自认为无所不能
But you thought you were invincible.
所以我才退出的
And that's why I walked.
多高尚啊
How noble.
在我们看来
The way we see it,
你欠我们的
you owe us,
我们来讨债了
and we're here to collect.
就这样吗
So that's it?
你们要为那些陈年往事杀了我
You're gonna kill me over ancient history?
劳埃德  你是最厉害的开锁人
Lloyd, you're the best safecracker we know.
我们干嘛要杀你呢
Why would we want to kill you?
我们要开Everhold牌保险箱
We're gonna break into an Everhold safe.
好活儿
It's a high-road job.
我们需要你的金手指
We need your Midas touch.
实际上  这笔大有赚头
In fact, the score's so big,
事成之后  我们就逃出国
when we're done, we're leaving the country.
所以安排妥你的事
So get your affairs in order.
干嘛我现在不向警方
What's stopping me from going to the cops...
告发你们俩呢
about you two right now?
你家挺温馨的
It's a lovely home.
下次要拿的  会是跳动中的心脏
Next time we take something with a heartbeat.
你干什么
What are you doing?
他们威胁他的家人
They threatened his family.
我去把他们拿下
I'm taking 'em down.
别这么冲动行吗
Can you take it easy instead?
现在是光天化日  约翰
It's broad daylight, John.
距离我的辖区就两条街
We're two blocks away from my precinct.
这些家伙必须永远消失  卡特
These guys need to go away for a long time, Carter.
那就把他们抓获现行
Then catch them in the act.
现在他们只不过
Right now, all we've got
是在策划抢劫
is conspiracy to commit a robbery.
这还属于非法监听
And that's from an illegal wiretap.
不足以让这些家伙远离惠勒及其家人
It won't be enough to keep them from Wyler or his family.
那我就让他们明白
Then I'll make them understand
他们绝不能靠近他家人
they can never go near his family again.
好吧
Okay.
难道你打算一辈子盯着他的家人
So are you gonna watch this family forever
以确保他们乖乖听话吗
to make sure they listen?
明天  晚上十点
Tomorrow, 10:00 PM.
我们在十字路口接你
We'll pick you up at that intersection.
记得来  劳埃德
Be there, Lloyd.
我塞了个一次性手机在他们卡车上
I slipped a burner phone on their truck.
这样就能追踪他们了
We can track them with it.
一旦他们开始行动
If they make the wrong move,
我们就一网打尽
we'll grab them.
惠勒怎么办
What about Wyler?
他得自己做出决定
He's got a decision to make.
? It serve you right to suffer ?
? Serve you right to be alone ?
? Because you're still livin' ?
? In days done past and gone ?
康妮
? Yeah ?
惠勒再过一小时就该跟沃恩会合了  芬奇
Wyler's due to meet Vaughn in an hour, Finch.
如果他入伙了我们怎么办
What are we gonna do if he goes through with the job?
你有什么建议
What do you suggest?
把他的底儿漏出去
We take him out of the equation.
他在费城还被通缉着
He still has open warrants in Philly.
惠勒入狱后
With Wyler serving jail time,
沃恩也无计可施
there's not much Vaughn could do.
这会毁了他的家庭
We'd risk breaking up his family.
他们可能永远不会原谅他
They might never forgive him.
我知道正常人的生活
I know the prospect of a normal life
对我们来说遥不可及  里瑟先生
seems remote to people like us, Mr. Reese.
可惠勒还有机会保住他的生活
But Wyler still has a chance to preserve his.
格雷汉姆  你在吗
Graham? Are you in here?
格雷汉姆
Graham?
检查监控  芬奇
Check the cameras, Finch.
确认他是否离开了
Make sure he hasn't already left.
里瑟先生  恐怕惠勒已经替我们做了决定
Mr. Reese, I'm afraid Wyler's made our decision for us.
他十五分钟前离开了
He left 15 minutes ago.
避开了家里的摄像头
Avoided his own camera.
他要参与沃恩的抢劫
He's meeting Vaughn for the heist.
他命不长了  芬奇
His number's up, Finch.
一旦他打开了保险箱
When he's done cracking that safe,
沃恩没理由饶他性命
Vaughn's got no reason to keep him alive.
芬奇  我要惠勒的位置
Finch, I need to know where Wyler is.
伯恩赛德的卡车GPS定位在哪里
What's the GPS location on Burnside's pickup?
曼哈顿西部某处
Somewhere in hell's kitchen.
稍等
Hang on.
在拖吊场
It's an impound lot.
他们在收拾离开
They're pulling up stakes,
抹去所有痕迹
ditching all traces.
保险箱有线索吗
What about tracking the safe?
Everhold虽然保险箱造得好
Everhold may make a quality safe,
但防火墙实在有待提高
but their firewall leaves something to be desired.
我在看他们的客户名单
I'm looking at their client list.
曼哈顿有五十多个客户
There are more than 50 of them in Manhattan.
看一下那辆卡车的GPS记录
Roll back the GPS history on the pickup.
沃恩有可能在动手前
Vaughn might have done a drive-by
去目标地点最后踩下点
for final preparations on the job.
他们在中城区一家小酒馆前停了四个钟头
They parked for four hours outside a midtown bistro.
街对面是什么
What's across the street?
高层住宅
Residential high-rise.
去年42层装了Everhold牌保险箱
An Everhold safe was installed on the 42nd floor last year.
客户名叫  安弗・克莱里克
Client's name is... Enver Clerik.
我把地址发给你
I'm sending you the address.
我知道那栋楼
I know that building.
前台保安可不会让你随便进去
Front security desk is not gonna let you just walk in.
不过我能带你上楼
But I can get you upstairs.
我认识一个住在楼里的人
I know a guy who lives in the building.
一名律师  我帮他解决过行为失职的问题
Lawyer I untangled from a malpractice thing.
他对我有点意思
He's kind of sweet on me.
芬奇  我进去之前你能看到那个房间吗
Finch, any way to see into that room before I go in?
大楼网站上显示
Building's website boasts
所有房间都配有智能家居技术
that all units are equipped with smarthome technology.
用掌上设备遥控自己家
所以是的  我们肯定可以利用
So, yes, I'm sure there's something we can exploit.
好  给卡特电话  让她过去找我们
Good. Call Carter, have her meet us there.
真好  你家黄脸婆还能放你出来耍耍
Real nice of your old lady to let you come out and play.
拿枪干嘛
What do we need guns for?
我没告诉过你吗
Oh, didn't I tell you?
我们要进个热闹场子
We're walking into a hot one.
住这儿的人是个宝石商
Guy who lives here is a gem dealer.
他不在城里时
When he's not in town,
他侄子喜欢邀人聚会
his nephew likes to have people over,
炫耀这里的景致
show off the view of the place.
这个可以进行"骚乱人群控制"
These are for what's called "Crowd Control".
看来你忘记给我准备面罩了
I guess you forgot a mask for me.
我一定是数错了
I must have miscounted.
抱歉了  兄弟
Sorry, buddy.
-我相信你不是故意的  -走吧  伙计们
- Honest mistake, I'm sure. - Let's go, boys.
-所有人都到墙角去  马上  -快
- Everyone in the corner! Now! - Let's go!
手机  珠宝  钱包都放进去  快
Cell phones, jewelry, wallets in the bag now! Come on!
指望着别的人今晚出现吗
You expecting anyone else to show up tonight?
没有
No.
我知道你们想要什么
Listen, I know what you want.
我不知道密码
I don't know the combination.
没人问你
Nobody asked you!
你肯定没想到自己
Bet you never thought you'd be trying
会再战江湖吧
to get on the other side of one of these again.
要我做这个
If I'm gonna do this,
得保持安静
it needs to be quiet.
闭嘴  否则我就开枪了
Shut up or get shot!
看你的了  大师
It's all yours, Maestro.
你在哪儿  芬奇
Where are you, Finch?
已经进来了  里瑟先生
Already inside, Mr. Reese.
我得看看他们的系统是如何加密的
I need to see just how encrypted their system is,
所以还需要点时间
so give me a moment.
这也是抓获现形的法子
This is one way of catching them in the act.
所有人都在42楼
Everyone's up on the 42nd floor.
我一把惠勒救出来
Soon as I pull Wyler out of there,
你就安排围捕那伙人
be ready to round up the crew.
你真当这易如反常吗
You really think it's gonna be that simple?
有点信心嘛
Have a little faith.
我们之前无缘认识
We haven't had the pleasure of meeting.
-我是卡特警探  -我是佐伊
- I'm Detective Carter. - Zoe.
约翰的妻子
John's wife.
说来话长
Long story.
-鲁珀特  -晚上好  摩根小姐
- Rupert. - Good evening, Miss Morgan.
他正在等您和您的朋友
He's expecting you and your friend.
我知道  你想念我
I know. You missed me.
我和我的朋友现在上去
My friend and I are on our way up.
你跟他说我是谁
Who did you say I was?
莎文娜  跳艳舞的
Savannah. An exotic dancer.
彩蛋一枚  Savannah是JC今年主演的电影  待上映中
抱歉了  鲁珀特
Sorry, Rupert.
计划略有改动
Slight change of plans.
情况如何  芬奇
How's it coming, Finch?
正在扫描克莱里克先生公寓里的全部设备
I'm scanning all the devices in Mr. Clerik's apartment.
似乎他的电视机有个摄像头
Looks like his television is equipped with a camera.
要是我获取他视频聊天软件的权限
If I can access the video chat software,
应该能够激活打开摄像头
I may be able to trick the camera into turning itself on.
网络摄像头设定
有画面了
And we have eyes.
里瑟先生  他们有人质
Mr. Reese, they've got hostages,
还有另外两名持枪凶犯
and there are two other armed men.
我想你应该无法
I don't think you're gonna be able
从正门长驱直入
to simply walk through the front door.
也没那打算
Wasn't planning on it.
去查看一下  快
Go check that out. Now.
我拿到密码的数字了
I got the numbers.
现在得弄清顺序
Now I got to find the order.
要多长时间
How much longer?
该多长就多长
As long as it takes.
我进来了  芬奇
I'm in, Finch.
这么久才回来
Took you long enough!
别管了  我们就快了
Forget about it. We're almost outta here.
放松  放松
Relax! Relax!
是什么
What is it?
好像是开关
Might be a switch.
紧急按钮之类的
Some kind of panic button.
恐怕正是如此  里瑟先生
I'm afraid that's correct, Mr. Reese.Dialogue: 0,0:35:20.28,0:35:20.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,紧急按钮启动
紧急按钮启动
网络电话正在拔号到
The VoIP is dialing out
应急宽带网络
to an emergency broadband network.
就算我取消也没用  电话已经打出去了
Even if I cancelled it, the call's already gone.
警探  我相信你还在监测警方频率
Detective, I trust that you're still monitoring the police bands?
对  我听到抢劫报案了
Yeah, I heard the robbery call.
几分钟后他们就会到
Only got a few minutes before they show up.
楼上情况如何
What's the situation like upstairs?
微妙得很
Delicate.
既然他报警了
If he's alerted the cops,
那就算了  我们快走
that's it then, we're out of here.
你得先打开保险箱
Not till you open that safe.
你还想再进监狱吗
Do you wanna go to jail again?
要是我们留下  你保证能如愿
'cause that's what's gonna happen if we stay here.
几时轮到你发号施令了
When did you start calling the shots?
唯一不同的是
All that's changed
你现在只有三分钟时间打开保险箱
is you've got three minutes to open that safe.
不
No.
打开
Open it.
否则我现在就杀了你
Or I kill you right now.
我听到警笛声了
I'm hearing sirens.
我是不是得把约翰跟那伙人一起逮捕了
Am I gonna have to arrest John with the crew?
最好不要
Preferably not.
要是警察在他逃离前到达
In the event that the police arrive before he escapes...
差一点就达成
Almost made it
你们两口子一整天不要求我犯法的光辉纪录了
a whole day without you two asking me to break the law.
我尽力吧
I'll see what I can do.
谢谢你  警探
Thank you, Detective.
这些人快狗急跳墙了  哈罗德
These guys are getting jumpy, Harold.
有什么办法引开他们的注意力
What do you got in the way of a distraction?
正在设法
I'm working on it.
搞定了
Got it.
果然是金手指
Man with the Midas touch.
我手上拿着价值两千万的蓝榴石
I'm holding 20 million worth of blue garnets in my hand.
我太想念你了  劳埃德
I missed you, Lloyd.
我还真没有同感
Wish I could say the same.
芬奇  该你动手了
Finch, I think that's your cue.
发送音频文件到环绕声系统
Sending an audio file to the surround sound system.
可能会很吵
This might get loud.
你毁了我的生活
You ruined my life...
为你自己开创了新生活
so you could start yourself a new one.
这样算扯平
This'll square it up.
天啊
God!
你要开枪吗
You gonna shoot me?
太久了
It's been so long,
你大概已经忘了怎么开枪
you probably don't remember how that thing works.
你并不想那么做的
You don't want to do that.
卡特警探  现场指挥官
Detective Carter, on-scene commander.
我盯这伙人一周了  所有人跟上
I've been on this crew all week. Everybody on me.
我们从西侧楼梯上去  明白吗
We're gonna take the west stairwell up, got it?
明白
Got it.
放他走  格雷汉姆
Let him go, Graham.
我不能
I can't.
这一切必须结束
This has to end.
如果你开枪  格雷汉姆・惠勒
If you pull that trigger, then Graham Wyler--
也就是真正的你  会和他一起死去
the man you really are-- dies with him.
他不能再骚扰我的家人
He can't come after my family again.
他不会
He won't.
他会在监狱里度过三十年
He'll spend the next three decades in prison.
但是如果你动手  就会跟他一起进去
But if you do this, you'll be right there with him.
康妮该怎么办呢
What's Connie gonna do then?
我就知道你下不了手
I knew you didn't have it in you.
你一直都是
You were always--
好人
The better man.
卡特
东侧楼梯安全
快走
Come on.
出口安全  里瑟先生
Your exit is clear, Mr. Reese.
我在街角的车里等
I'm waiting in a car around the corner.
继续走
Keep moving.
没时间了
There's not much time.
你是谁
Who are you?
带你回家的人
Your ride home.
我留了字条  告诉了她一切
I left a note telling her everything.
我是谁  我做过什么
Who I was, what I'd done.
我能像什么都没发生一样回去吗
I'm supposed to go back like nothing's ever happened?
康妮和伊西能忘记
Connie and Izzy forget
她们所认识的我完全是个假象吗
that everything they know about me is a lie?
并非完全
Not everything.
她们对你的意义  是真的
What they mean to you, that's real.
她们知道
They know that.
那无法改变我的过去
Can't change what I've done.
过去是很难逃避的
The past is a difficult thing to outrun.
也许是时候停止再逃了
Maybe it's time to stop running.
格雷汉姆  你不必非这么做
Graham... you don't have to do this.
我必须
Yeah, I do.
惠勒不再躲藏了  芬奇
Wyler's done hiding, Finch.
他刚刚去自首了
He just turned himself in.
他是决定了要自首
He may have decided to turn himself in,
不过你还是要赶快离开
but you need to get out of there.
惠勒成为了污点证人
Wyler's turning state's evidence
希望能获得减刑
in hopes for a reduced sentence.
看来现在要由法庭来决定什么对他最好了
I suppose now the courts will decide what's best for him.
你好  约翰
Oh, hi, John.
康妮
Connie.
我想和格雷汉姆谈谈
I was wondering if I could talk to Graham.
他告诉我你救了他
He told me you helped him out.
没说怎么救的
Didn't say how.
无论你是如何
But whatever you did...
不用谢
You're welcome.
你要离开了
See you're moving on.
是啊
Yep.
我这种人不适合郊区
Guy like me doesn't belong in the suburbs.
只是来道个别
Just wanted to say good-bye.
我只能停在这里
This my stop.
不像你  我可是真的被钉牢在这里了
Unlike you, I'm stuck here literally.
法官认为我对社会无害
Judge didn't think I was a danger to society,
所以我要用修剪草坪来还债
so I get to pay my debt mowing the lawn.
格雷汉姆
Graham?
洗衣机又有噪音了
The washer's making that noise again.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
我让她承受了太多
I put her through a lot.
不管什么原因
And for whatever reason,
当我早上醒来时  她还在身边
she's still there when I wake up in the morning.
我想这足以证明什么
Guess that says something.
保重  约翰
Take care, John.
我们现在该离婚了吧
This the part where we get divorced?
真遗憾没成
Sorry it didn't work out.
过程还是挺有趣的
Fun while it lasted though.
是吧
Right?
我们还剩下些威士忌
Well, we still have some Scotch left.
想不想再待一个晚上
Want to stay one more night?
试试把钱赢回去
Try to win some of that money back?
? It serve you right to suffer ?
? Serve you right to be alone ?
我猜猜  一份香草冰淇淋
Let me guess, one vanilla cone.
是的  谢谢
Yes, please.
就算在一月
Even in January,
我也会为你留上几份
I always keep a few of these for when you come by.
我真的那么好预测吗
Am I really that predictable?
不  你只是不愿拒绝小小的乐趣
No, you just don't deny yourself small pleasures.
你大概是第一个这么说我的人
You may be the first person that ever told me that.
这没什么错
Nothing wrong with it.
生命只有一次  对吧
You only live once, right?
? Serve you right to be alone ?
? Because you are still livin' ?
亨德里克斯  格蕾斯  R
? days done past and gone ?
? Every time you see a woman ?
? She make you think of yours ?
你好
Hello.